Davide RAVOTTI

PERSONAL DATA

ADDRESS: Faculty of Mathematics, University of Vienna

9 Oskar Morgenstern-Platz 1, 1090 Wien Austria

NATIONALITY: Italian

EMAIL: davide.ravotti@gmail.com

davide.ravotti@univie.ac.at

WEBSITE: https://davideravotti.github.io/

SCIENTIFIC INTERESTS

My research focuses on the ergodic theory of smooth parabolic flows, including locally Hamiltonian flows on surfaces, unipotent flows on quotients of semisimple Lie groups, nilflows on nilmanifolds, and their smooth perturbations. I am also interested in the following topics:

• Distributional limit theorems for dynamical systems.

• Infinite ergodic theory.

· Rigidity phenomena in homogeneous dynamics.

EDUCATION

2018 | Ph.D. degree at the University of Bristol (Bristol, UK).

Supervisor: prof. Corinna Ulcigrai.

Thesis title: *Mixing via shearing in some parabolic flows*. This thesis received a *Faculty of Science Commendation*.

2014 | Diploma di Licenza of the Scuola Superiore of the University of Udine

(Udine, Italy).

Final mark: 110/110 cum laude.

2013 | Master degree in Mathematics, University of Udine (Udine, Italy).

Final mark: 110/110 cum laude.

2011 Bachelor degree in Mathematics, University of Udine (Udine, Italy).

Final mark: 110/110 cum laude.

ACADEMIC POSITIONS

JUN. 2021-PRESENT Postdoctoral Assistant, University of Vienna (Vienna, Austria).

MAR 2019-MAY 2021 Research Fellow, Monash University (Melbourne, Australia).

SEP. 2018-MAR 2019 Postdoctoral Assistant, University of Zürich (Zürich, Switzerland).

APR 2018-Aug. 2018 Research Associate, University of Bristol (Bristol, UK).

FUNDED RESEARCH PROJECTS AS PI

AZRIELI FELLOWSHIP 2021-2023 (declined).

ESI RESEARCH IN TEAMS 2023 (together with H. Bruin, D. Terhesiu, and C. Fougeron).

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

PREPRINTS:

- [13] M. Artigiani, L. Flaminio, D. Ravotti. On rigidity properties of time-changes of unipotent flows. Preprint, 2022 (*arxiv*:2209.01253).
- [12] E. Corso, D. Ravotti. Large hyperbolic circles. Preprint, 2022 (arxiv:2208.07771).
- [11] L. Flaminio, D. Ravotti. Abelian covers of hyperbolic surfaces: equidistribution of spectra and infinite mixing asymptotics for horocycle flows. Preprint, 2022 (*arxiv:2207.08263*).

PUBLISHED/ACCEPTED:

- [10] D. Ravotti. Asymptotics and limit theorems for horocycle ergodic integrals à la Ratner (with an appendix by Emilio Corso). *Journal de l'École polytechnique Mathématiques*, Vol. 10:305-334, 2023.
- [9] P. Giulietti, A. Hammerlindl, D. Ravotti. Quantitative global-local mixing for accessible skew products. *Ann. Henri Poincaré*, 23(3):923–971, 2022.
- [8] D. Ravotti. Polynomial mixing for time-changes of unipotent flows. *Ann. Sc. Norm. Super. Pisa Cl. Sci.* (5), Vol. XXIII(3):1491–1506, 2022.
- [7] A. Avila, G. Forni, D. Ravotti, C. Ulcigrai. Mixing for smooth time-changes of general nilflows. *Adv. Math.*, 385, 107759, 2021.
- [6] D. Ravotti. Quantitative equidistribution of horocycle push-forwards of transverse arcs. *Enseign. Math.*, 66(1-2):135–150, 2020.
- [5] A. Kanigowski, D. Ravotti. Polynomial 3-mixing for smooth time-changes of horocycle flows. *Discrete Contin. Dyn. Syst.*, 40(9):5347–5371, 2020.
- [4] D. Ravotti. Parabolic perturbations of unipotent flows on compact quotients of $SL(3,\mathbb{R})$. *Comm. Math. Phys.*, 371(1):331–351, 2019.
- [3] D. Ravotti. Mixing for suspension flows over skew-translations and time-changes of quasi-abelian filiform nilflows. *Ergod. Theory Dyn. Syst.*, 39(12):3407–3436, 2019.
- [2] D. Ravotti. Quantitative mixing for locally Hamiltonian flows with saddle loops on compact surfaces. *Ann. Henri Poincaré*, 18(12):3815–3861, 2017.
- [1] G. Panti, D. Ravotti. Measures induced by units. J. Symb. Log., 78(3):886-910, 2013.

OTHER WRITINGS:

- [a] D. Ravotti. Introduction to Homogeneous Dynamics. Lecture notes for the course given at the University of Vienna, 2022.
- [b] D. Ravotti. Mixing via shearing in some parabolic flows. Ph.D. thesis (*Faculty of Science Commendation*), University of Bristol, 2018.

SEMINARS

28 FEB. 2023	University of Graz (Graz, Austria).
16 FEB. 2023	University of Pisa (Pisa, Italy).
17 JAN. 2023	Nicolaus Copernicus University (Torun, Poland).
16 Nov. 2022	Tsinghua University (online seminar).
06 Ост. 2022	KTH (online seminar).
18 Jul. 2022	Conference "Summer Topology Conference" (Vienna, Austria).
29 Jun. 2022	Workshop "Ruelle Resonances in Parabolic Dynamics" (Zürich, Switzerland).
13 MAY 2022	Jagiellonian University in Krakow (online seminar).

Université de Lille (Lille, France). 29 Apr. 2022 IST Austria (Klosteneuburg, Austria). 25 Apr. 2022 Workshop "Dynamics, Foliations, and Geometry II" (Regensburg, Germany). 04 FEB. 2022 30 JAN. 2022 Budapest-Wien Seminar (Wien, Austria). 04 OCT. 2021 University of Zürich (Zürich, Switzerland). UNSW Pure Math Seminar (online seminar). 09 MAR. 2021 08 OCT. 2020 Vienna Ergodic Seminar (online seminar). 02 JUL. 2020 Sydney Dynamics Group (online seminar). University of Maryland (online seminar). 23 APR. 2020 Monash University (online seminar). 22 Apr. 2020 05 DEC. 2019 Conference "AustMS 2019" (Melbourne, Australia). Conference "Smooth and Homogeneous Dynamics" (Bangalore, India). 23 SEP. 2019 Conference "Dynamics of Parabolic Flows" (Zürich, Switzerland). 01 JUL. 2019 27 MAR. 2019 Monash University (Melbourne, Australia). Scuola Normale Superiore (Pisa, Italy). 05 DEC. 2018 03 SEP. 2018 Conference "Dynamics Days Europe" (Loughborough, UK). Queen Mary University (London, UK). 16 JAN. 2018 02 Nov. 2017 Scuola Normale Superiore (Pisa, Italy). University of Warwick (Coventry, UK). 17 Oct. 2017 University of Manchester (Manchester, UK). 12 Oct. 2017 Conference "Dynamics in Number Theory and Geometry" (Kingston, 24 AUG. 2017 Workshop "Modern Trends in the Ergodic Theory of Dynamical Systems" 06 JUN. 2017 (Rome, Italy). University of Bristol (Bristol, UK). 23 MAR. 2017 One-day Workshop on Dynamical Systems, ICTP (Trieste, Italy). 11 JAN. 2017 10 JAN. 2017 University of Udine (Udine, Italy).

TEACHING AND OTHER ACTIVITIES

STUDENT SUPERVISION:

University of Vienna Bachelor Thesis of Gibeom Kim

Thesis title: Discrete time Markov chains and applications

Graduated in 2023.

LECTURER:

University of Vienna Ergodic Theory (together with H. Bruin), 2023.

Measure and Integration Theory (together with H. Bruin), 2022.

Homogeneous Dynamics, 2022.

Monash University Metric spaces, Banach spaces, Hilbert spaces (together with J. Clut-

terbuck), 2020.

ICTP Summer School Ergodic theory minicourse (together with O. Butterley, I. Pasquinelli,

S. Luzzatto, and L. Simonelli), July 2019.

Lecture recording is available at https://www.youtube.com/

watch?v=PjFpuDiVL1U.

TUTOR (PROBLEM CLASSES):

University of Vienna Basic concepts of Topology, 2021.

Monash University Metric spaces, Banach spaces, Hilbert spaces, 2020.

Mathematics Learning Center, 2019-2020.

Univeristy of Zürich Dynamical Systems and Ergodic Theory, 2019. Univeristy of Bristol Analysis 1 and Foundations and Proof, 2018.

Analysis 1, Foundations and Proof, and Introduction to Geometry, 2017.

Analysis 1 and Linear Algebra and Geometry, 2016.

SERVICE TO THE COMMUNITY

Referee for: Inventiones Mathematicae, Journal of Modern Dynamics, Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems, Monatshefte für Mathematik, Discrete and Continuous Dynamical Systems.

Reviewer for MathSciNet.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

ITALIAN (native language).

ENGLISH (full professional proficiency).

FRENCH (basic).

GERMAN (basic).

SPANISH (basic).

JAPANESE (basić).